<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
<channel>
<title>Project Euler</title>
<atom:link href="http://projecteuler.net/rss2_euler.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><link>http://projecteuler.net</link>
<description>A website dedicated to the fascinating world of mathematics and programming.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>projecteuler.net</copyright>
<webMaster>no_reply@projecteuler.net (Colin Hughes)</webMaster>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 05:09:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>60</ttl>
<item>
<title>New Problem 493</title>
<link>http://projecteuler.net/problem=493</link>
<description>Release date: Sat, 13 Dec 2014 16:00:00 +0000</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">problem_id_493</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Emergency Account Recovery Key</title>
<link>http://projecteuler.net/news</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <p><p>Since we no longer store any personal information in the database it has not been possible to gain access to your account if you forget your password. It is also possible that some members have changed their username and after a period of absence from Project Euler they have forgotten what they changed it to.</p>

<p>To help members protect against accidentally losing access to their own accounts we have introduced an emergency account recovery key. If you have not done so already then the Account tab in the menu bar should be highlighted to indicate that something needs to be done. When you visit your account page you will be prompted to generate your key. After clicking the button you will be presented with your own personal randomly generated key and advised that after making a careful note of it to store it in a safe location.</p>

<p>In order to protect your account only a hash of your key is stored in the database. This means that the server will be unable to display your key again once you navigate away from that page.</p>

<p>In the event of losing your password and/or username then you will find an additional link on the Sign In page to recover your account. On that page you will need to enter the entire key, and correctly enter a CAPTCHA code. If the key is authenticated then on the next page you will be reminded of your username and a new password will be generated.</p>

<p>Your key will continue to work as often as you need it, but if you suspect that it has been compromised then you can generate a new key on your account page. But please be aware that generating a new key will make the old key invalid.</p>

<p>You are personally responsible for safe-guarding your own key and it is the only alternative mechanism available to gain access to your account in the event of losing your primary sign-in credentials.</p> ]]>
(Monday 15 September 2014: Emergency Account Recovery Key)</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">news_id_73</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Remember Me, HTTPS, and Privacy Policy</title>
<link>http://projecteuler.net/news</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <p><p>Many members will be pleased to see that the &quot;Remember Me&quot; feature has been restored. When you sign in now you can tick the box to keep your session alive. You can sign out in the normal way, otherwise your session will remain active for up to 30 days of inactivity.</p>

<p>You may also have noticed that the default connection to the website is now secure (HTTPS). It is still possible to switch between non-secure and secure using the padlock icon in the top right corner of each page.</p>

<p>In order for these features to be enabled it has been necessary to use cookies. At the bottom of each page, next to the link for copyright information, a new link has been added to outline our <a href="privacy">privacy policy</a>. This explains in details which cookies are used, what data is stored in the database, and what information is public by default.</p></p> ]]>
(Monday 08 September 2014: Remember Me, HTTPS, and Privacy Policy)</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">news_id_72</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Privacy Option</title>
<link>http://projecteuler.net/news</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <p><p>As some people value their privacy, we have set an option in the maintenance section of the account page which allows you to make your account private. Once you have chosen to do this, your username will not appear in any public ranked tables (including the fastest solvers), nor will you be included in any of the statistics (levels and awards). But please note that this action is permanent; it cannot be reversed!</p>

<p>In addition to privacy, this feature has also been implemented for the sake of fairness. Cheating undermines the honest, hard work of the vast majority of members who take great pride in their own effort in solving the problems. It also skews the statistics, as it gives a false representation of those who have actually earned different levels/awards.</p>

<p>Some members choose to cheat for a number of reasons, and that is a personal choice. So if you find yourself in this minority group, then by voluntarily setting your account to private your progress will not be monitored and you will be free to use other people's answers to "solve" the problems.</p></p> ]]>
(Sunday 31 August 2014: Privacy Option)</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">news_id_71</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Publication of new problems</title>
<link>http://projecteuler.net/news</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <p><p>We're glad to announce that new problems are going to be published again.<br />
Problems 477 and 478 were originally planned for June 2014.<br />
Problem 477 will now be published Sat, 23 August, 16:00 (server time)<br />
Problem 478 will be published Sat, 30 August, 19:00 (server time)</p>
</p> ]]>
(Monday 18 August 2014: Publication of new problems)</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">news_id_70</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Update (Project Euler Returns)</title>
<link>http://projecteuler.net/news</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <p><p>Since the return of Project Euler it seems that everything has gone well. As expected, some minor glitches were reported, but they have all been fixed. I would like to thank the members who took the time to report them.</p>

<p>It is worth pointing out that one of those glitches related to password checking and a small number of members were unable to sign in using their old passwords. This bug has now been fixed so if you tried to sign in yesterday and were unable to then it is quite possible you were a victim of this bug and you should try again.</p>

<p>In addition, the number of requests for password resets from members who have solved 200+ problems was very small and almost all of those were victims of the password checking bug. As a result, from today the threshold is being lowered to 100+ problems. Obviously by increasing the number members eligible also increases the potential number of requests, so if you make a request (link found on the Sign In page) then please be patient as each request is handled manually.</p></p> ]]>
(Sunday 17 August 2014: Update (Project Euler Returns))</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">news_id_69</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>